<Document>
  # Felinids

   ### Homeworld
  Unknown

  ### Temperment
  Felinids vary almost as much as humans when it comes to how they are viewed, with two main assumptions aside.  Felinids are generally assumed to be more grumpy than the average human - or - much more affectionate than the average human.

  ### Secondary Species of Interest
  Harpy - Harpies have a tendency to become randomly infatuated with Felinids, neither species knows why - but one thing is for sure.  Felinids wish it would stop more often than not.

  Vulpkanin - With both species being focused heavily on space trade the Felinids and their Vulpkanin 'friends' tend to be at arms length, even if the Vulpkanin seem to think this is some sort of 'happy game'.

  Rodentia - The game of cat and mouse is ancient in human circles - and it is true here to a degree as well.  Most Felinids love teasing Rodentia, be that physically or verbally.


  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobFelinidDummy" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  Small and mischievous cat-eared people. Being small in itself has lots of upsides and downsides. They can hide inside duffelbags.

  ## Diet

  - Can eat raw meat.
  - Will get poisoned by Theobromine (Chocolate, Tea, Coffee) and Allicin (Onion, Garlic).

  ## Benefits

  - They are smaller than Humans, making them harder to hit.
  - Can fit in duffelbags.
  - Have the ability to throw up an hairball to get rid of some of the chemicals from their bloodstream.
  - Able to eat mice and rats after picking them up. This has the benefit of regenerating the hairball ability and feeding them.
  - Uses their claws to do Slashing damage and Piercing damage.
  - Can walk completely silently, but only while barefooted.
  - Immunity to the OwOnavirus disease.

  ## Drawbacks

  - Takes 15% more Blunt, Slash and Piercing damage.
  - Are easily shoved, pushed and carried around by every other morphotypes due to their small size.
  - They are weaker and struggle to carry and pull things due to their small size. They are unable to carry an Oni.
  - They have slightly less stamina than Humans.

</Document>
