<Document>
# Welcome to the Coyote Sector!
[italic]In the year 2525 countless spacers flock for the frontier for a chance at a better life. Away from the busy starports and crowded cities of the core worlds and into the tantalizing and unforgiving blackness of space. Coyote is one of many star systems amongst the frontier, teeming with long forgotten riches and unpredictable dangers.You’re one of many such spacers.  Find a ship, find a crew, find a way to make money. You’re only truly free as long as you aren’t broke.[/italic]

Coyote Sector is based loosely around [color=#a4885c]Paradise Station[/color] lore. It takes place in 2525 (500 years from today's date.) and a scant 80 years after the [color=#a4885c]Cygni Rebellion[/color]. The frontier is the war-torn void between the two major stellar polities, [textlink="The Trans Solar Federation" link="SolGov"] and [textlink="The Union of Soviet Socialist Planets" link="USSP"]. Much is to be decided about this system, but it's proximity to [color=#a4885c]Epsilon Eradani[/color] means that [textlink="Nanotrasen" link="NT"] has the most say in that matter.

The star system Coyote was (like many systems out here) rediscovered after the war. It's governorship awarded to one [color=#a4885c]Victor Coyote[/color] of [color=#a4885c]NT[/color] fame before anyone even recovered its name. It's principle starport [color=#a4885c]Nash[/color] is seated within the gravity well of the star systems gas giant, [color=#a4885c]Bowie[/color]. Only four of it's twenty-somewhat planets are inhabited, [color=#a4885c]Dallus[/color], [color=#a4885c]Garland[/color], [color=#a4885c]New Boston[/color], and [color=#a4885c]Redwater[/color]. Altogether the star systems population barely makes up a few million people.

[color=#a4885c]Nash[/color] has a handful of orbital support structures, [color=#a4885c]St. Michaels Hospital[/color] and [color=#a4885c]the New Frontier Sherifs Department.[/color]. [color=#a4885c]Nash[/color] itself is owned and operated by [color=#a4885c]NT[/color]

[color=#a4885c]The NFSD[/color] is owned by [color=#a4885c]The TSF[/color], and provides what little law enforcement the frontier sees. They're also the only thing representing [color=#a4885c]TSF[/color] interests out here.

[color=#a4885c]St. Michaels Hospital[/color] is owned and operated by [color=#a4885c]The United Health Services[/color], a publicly funded (and NT backed) coop to provide healthcare to those in need.
</Document>
