<Document>
  #Frontier Station Rules

  [color=red]If any of the links do not work use the guidebook version on the escape or (Numpad 0) menus. [/color]

  [color=red]These rules are expected to be read in their entirety.[/color]

  ## 1: Overview
  - This is an 18+ server, you must be an adult and act like one.
  this is an English speaking server. Conversations and media sharing in languages other than English are prohibited in the interest of moderation. Common colloquialisms and official media such as movies and songs are allowed at moderator discretion.
  You are expected to follow all Discord TOS and US federal law.

  ## 2: Administration

  - If you encounter an issue, adminhelp in a timely manner to ensure the situation can be properly handled.
    Concerns may be more difficult or impossible to address after several days have passed.
  - Do not discuss or reference moderative action in any public space in or out of the discord server.
  - All administrators have the final say on any rulings. You are expected to cooperate to the fullest extent
    even if you believe the situation is unfair. You may bring up any concerns regarding admin treatment in an official ticket to be investigated.

  ## 3: Community Behavior
  - Malicious activities such as harassment, spamming, insults, and unnecessary hostility toward other users is strictly prohibited.
  - Criticism toward developer projects must be made with respect and must be constructive.
  - Do not impersonate staff, other users, or known figures, even in jest.

  ## 4: Content Restrictions
 - Respect the function of each discord channel and post only where appropriate. NSFW conversations and content are prohibited in general-chat , media , and memes
 - advertising, promoting, or recruiting for other servers, communities, or external platforms is prohibited without admin approval.
 - The following topics are strictly prohibited in all text, voice, and media channels: Outside drama, including politics. Hatespeech and slurs. All underage content.
 Child or animal abuse. Excessive gore. suicide, including the terms KYS, KMS, and the LTG meme and its variants or references. Abortion and miscarriage, including the Loss meme and its variants or references.

  ## 5: Qualitative Player Rule
  - Administrators have the final say in rulings and decisions. Attempting to skirt the rules will still result in punishment. It's about the spirit, not the law.
  - Ahelp if you have any questions involving rules or permission.
  - If you have a problem, or a rule has been broken, please use a ticket.
  - If you have a problem with an admin abusing their privileges, take it to a ticket and request the headmins.
  - If you have a problem with the headmins, take it to a ticket with the directors.
  - Alt accounts, proxies, cheats, ban evasion are strictly prohibited.
  - Do not exploit game mechanics, bugs, tricks, unintended features.

  ## 6: Be The Player You Want To See
  - Names must be original and not references, memes, hard to read, etc.
  - No netspeak or emoticons outside ingame written text.
  - Respect the wishes of others in LOOC.
  - Provide a NSFW tag on linked refs.
  - Heavy topics such as suicide or abuse are strictly forbbiden.
  - Additionally, do not use mental disorders as justification for amoral behavior.
  - Don't play excessively hostile or provocative characters.
  - No spamming radio or text channels.
  - Do not interact with SSD/AFK players at all without administrative permission.
  - Do not ghost to spy on other players.

  ## 7: PvP
  - DO NOT break into shuttered ships or bolted dorms.
  - EORG is strictly forbidden.
  - No hostility, conflict, or killing without justification and escalation. If you seperate, you must escalate again.
  - Follow proper escalation. TALK / WARN / THREATEN. The DEFENDER of the escalation chooses the highest level. If the defender talks shit and peels off, you can't skip straight to warning or threatening them. Match. Their. Energy.

  ## 8: Meta
  - Do not metacomm. Posting in round information is only acceptable in the IC discord channels.
  - Do not metagrudge.
  - Maintain the seperation between IC and OOC. Your character is simply not you.
  - Do not use the information gathered while ghosting or dead.

</Document>
