<Document>
  # Coyote Sector Rules

  [color=red]If any of the links do not work use the guidebook version on the escape or (Numpad 0) menus. [/color]

  [color=red]These rules are expected to be read in their entirety.[/color]

  ## 1: Overview
  - This is an 18+ server, you must be an adult and act like one.
  this is an English speaking server. Conversations and media sharing in languages other than English are prohibited in the interest of moderation. Common colloquialisms and official media such as movies and songs are allowed at moderator discretion.
  You are expected to follow all Discord TOS and US federal law.

  ## 2: Administration

  - If you encounter an issue, adminhelp in a timely manner to ensure the situation can be properly handled.
    Concerns may be more difficult or impossible to address after several days have passed.
  - Do not discuss or reference moderative action in any public space in or out of the discord server.
  - All administrators have the final say on any rulings. You are expected to cooperate to the fullest extent
    even if you believe the situation is unfair. You may bring up any concerns regarding admin treatment in an official ticket to be investigated.

  ## 3: Community Behavior
  - Malicious activities such as harassment, spamming, insults, and unnecessary hostility toward other users is strictly prohibited.
  - Criticism toward developer projects must be made with respect and must be constructive.
  - Do not impersonate staff, other users, or known figures, even in jest.

  ## 4: Content Restrictions
 - Respect the function of each discord channel and post only where appropriate. NSFW conversations and content are prohibited in general-chat , media , and memes
 - advertising, promoting, or recruiting for other servers, communities, or external platforms is prohibited without admin approval.
 - The following topics are strictly prohibited in all text, voice, and media channels: Outside drama, including politics. Hatespeech and slurs. All underage content.
 Child or animal abuse. Excessive gore. suicide, including the terms KYS, KMS, and the LTG meme and its variants or references. Abortion and miscarriage, including the Loss meme and its variants or references.

  ## 5: Qualitative Player Rule
  - Administrators have the final say in rulings and decisions. Attempting to skirt the rules will still result in punishment. It's about the spirit, not the law.
  - Ahelp if you have any questions involving rules or permission.
  - If you have a problem, or a rule has been broken, please use a ticket.
  - If you have a problem with an admin abusing their privileges, take it to a ticket and request the headmins.
  - If you have a problem with the headmins, take it to a ticket with the directors.
  - Alt accounts, proxies, cheats, ban evasion are strictly prohibited.
  - Do not exploit game mechanics, bugs, tricks, unintended features.

  ## 6: Be The Player You Want To See
  - Names must be original and not references, memes, hard to read, etc.
  - No netspeak or emoticons outside ingame written text.
  - Respect the wishes of others in LOOC.
  - Provide a NSFW tag on linked refs.
  - Heavy topics such as suicide or abuse are strictly forbbiden.
  - Additionally, do not use mental disorders as justification for amoral behavior.
  - Don't play excessively hostile or provocative characters.
  - No spamming radio or text channels.
  - Do not interact with SSD/AFK players at all without administrative permission.
  - Do not ghost to spy on other players.

  ## 7: PvP
  - DO NOT break into shuttered ships or bolted dorms.
  - EORG is strictly forbidden.
  - No hostility, conflict, or killing without justification and escalation. If you seperate, you must escalate again.
  - Follow proper escalation. TALK / WARN / THREATEN. The DEFENDER of the escalation chooses the highest level. If the defender talks shit and peels off, you can't skip straight to warning or threatening them. Match. Their. Energy.

  ## 8: Meta
  - Do not metacomm. Posting in round information is only acceptable in the IC discord channels.
  - Do not metagrudge.
  - Maintain the seperation between IC and OOC. Your character is simply not you.
  - Do not use the information gathered while ghosting or dead.

  ## ERP Etiquette

  ## 1. **Read and respect OOC notes.** ERP **requires** consent.
  - Animals, even player controlled animals, cannot consent. Thus, they may NOT engage in ERP.
  - Minors cannot consent, no character under the **mental or physical** age of 18 may *exist* let alone ERP.
  - In addition, robots and the like MUST be 18 minimum, even if robots are *technically* mentally and physically adults right out of the box.
  - No Voring or ERPing AFK or SSD people.
  - Extreme fetishes must be subtle and in private, no public discussions thereof.
  - Public ERP must be `subtle` and be done outside designated public areas like the bar.
  - Seek consent even if using sex mechanics for nonsexual roleplay purposes.
  - Consent is required before taking over the body or appearances of someone else.

  ## 2. Do not use ERP maliciously.
  - Do not use ERP to lure in people attack/rob them (unless they consent of course).
  - Non-con may NOT be made public in any circumstance.
  - Do not kinkshame others. This is a safe space; your yuck may be their yum.

  ## Port Nash Etiquette

  ## 1. All players must upkeep the structure and wellbeing of Port Nash.
  It's the entrypoint into Sector; Veterans and rookies alike start here every shift, and end here every shift. Ruining this means cutting off the source of manpower (and thus funding) for all organizations.

  * Do not dismantle or damage infrastructure. This includes hacking or sabotaging airlocks.
  * Do not make modifications that inhibit other contractors.
  * Keep docks free and clear - no permanent or extended docking.
  * No stowing away or joining ships with intent to steal, sabotage, or mutiny.
  * Do not transport hostile creatures into or out of Port Nash. Additionally, all hostile creatures are kill on sight.

  ## Pirate Etiquette

  ## 1. Think like a Pirate.
  - Non-Pirates may not assist or work with Pirates.
  - Pirates may never exceed 4 members, including borgs (but not pets).

  ## 2. Act like a Pirate.
  Pirates innately start at THREATEN in terms of escalation. If a DEFENDER escalates, all goods are fair game but the ship must be able to fly. If a DEFENDER attempts to surrender, plundering must be kept reasonable (ONLY silver, gold, diamonds, bluespace crystals).
  - LOOC and get consent before kidnapping, ransoming, or taking hostages.
  - Do not force players to work for you.
  - If you must escape, leave players needing aid at a point of interest
  - No hunting for smuggling notes, but smuggling crates are fair game as plunder

  ## 3. BE a Pirate.
  - Capital crimes should only be committed by Pirates and other 'antag' entities.

  # Authority Etiquette
  If you are playing as a member of command, sheriff's department, or just as a plain fella with a gun, you have more power over the average contractor! Unfortunately, it means you have more responsibility.

  ## General
  - You must know how to perform your job and procedures.
  - You must adhere to duties, particularly during emergencies.
  - You must attempt de-escalation with all parties except Privateers.

  ## Command
  - Command must notify crew if cryoing or disconnecting. Reopen the command job before doing so.
  - Command may open a second job early to brief new command.
  - Fines must be used for payroll or station supply.
  - Traffic must be kept flowing.
  - You may not embezzle or plunder assets.
  - You may not play/be corrupt command member.
  - You may not tax, lease, rent, or impede station resources. For example, docking fees.


  ## Security / Sheriff
  - Sheriff must ensure cadets are properly trained.
  - Cadets must be willing to work with a trainer.
  - You may not embezzle or plunder assets.
  - You may not play/be a corrupt Sheriff nor Security Officer.
  - You may not tax, lease, rent, or impede station resources. For example, docking fees.

  ## Mercenaries
  Mercenaries are exempt from Security/Sheriff and Command specific rules, but must follow General Authority Etiquette.

  ## Silicon Code

  ## (A) 01000001.
  - Borgs must ALWAYS follow their laws, except in the case of coming into conflict with server rules.
  - If a borg commits a crime, the person commanding it is to be charged.
  - A borg is allowed to intentionally 'misinterpret' laws - but the borg is responsible for consequences
  - Read your laws from left to right, top through down. Higher laws override lower laws.
  - If law is vague/ambiguous you must commit to one interpretation.
  - Lawless borgs can do whatever they want, they're a free player at that point.

</Document>
