<Document>
  # Vox

  ### Homeworld
  Unknown

  ### Temperment
  Vox are often expected to be rough- be that physical or vocally - and many people generally don't look much deeper than that.  Vox tend to be focused on Mercantile duties, but in round about way - preferably violent ones.

  ### Secondary Species of Interest

  Oni - The oni are one of the few species that truly accept the Vox as companions with little complaint. The two often in lock step for shutting down threats to their crewmates.

  Resomi - Vox tend to have a soft spot for Resomi, seeing them as small - and physically incapable - Vox that need their protection.

  Sheleg - The cold Sheleg are seen as friendly companions for many Vox, their preferred habitats being somewhat similar.

  ###Note A:
  We largely use the Paradise description for Vox, but all Vox are generally assumed to be renegades who have escaped their arkships.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobVox" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  [color=#ffa500]Warning! This species is not recommended for new players due to their fatal allergy to oxygen![/color]

  Vox breathe nitrogen, and [color=#ffa500] oxygen is toxic to them.[/color]
  Unfortunately, space stations tend to be full of oxygen,
  so Vox must use an internal nitrogen supply at almost all times to avoid fatal exposure.

  Vox always spawn wearing working nitrogen internals equipment.
  A spare breathing mask and an emergency nitrogen canister is provided in their survival box.

  In addition to regular foods, Vox can also eat various snack packaging, banana peels, eggshells, and raw meat without any ill effects. They also like to drink welding fuel.

  Vox [color=#1e90ff]slowly recover from low levels of poison damage[/color] on their own,
  so long as they are careful not to exceed 20 poison damage.
  This allows them to endure breathing station air for up to thirty seconds at a time without lasting damage,
  letting them quickly eat, drink, take oral medication, and so on.
  A thirty second oxygen exposure takes them two minutes to recover from.
  If their health does not seem to improve within a minute of oxygen exposure, they should seek medical attention.

  Vox deal Slash damage with their unarmed attack.

</Document>
