<Document>
  # Roleplaying
  Ultimately we are expecting all players to be playing a character that exists seperate from themselves in the space of the server. Characters that have depth and personalities beyond just being a blank homunculus.

  But what is Roleplaying?  Well, based off a wikipedia description.

  A role-playing game (sometimes spelled roleplaying game, or abbreviated as RPG) is a game in which players assume the roles of characters in a fictional setting.
  Players take responsibility for acting out these roles within a narrative, either through literal acting or through a process of structured decision-making regarding character development.
  Actions taken within many games succeed or fail according to a formal system of rules and guidelines.

 # Characterization
  Characterization is the backbone of all roleplay, without it characters aren't characters.  They are simulacrums of people existing and acting in silence - but what IS characterization?

  Characterization is taking actions, through emotes, subtles, talking - or any other interactive systems that make an otherwise silent and immobile statue of a character seem alive.  Maybe you tap your foot when nervous.
  Maybe your character uses the word 'like' a lot, or you tilt your head when talking to people you like.  These tiny actions build up, they paint a picture of the character that is more than just the sprite you've put together in the character editor.
  More than just your quirks, or your loadout items. They take the homunculus of your design and put the soul into it. Deeper and more creative roleplay can not truly exist without characters acting at least partially like people, and Characterization is
  the key to that.

  So, with that in mind we have created an incentive system to build up a reason - beyond the desire for roleplay - that your character can be Characterizing.  We understand that in many ways the act of 'roleplaying' is unincentivized over 'playing the game',
  but with this system the two are locked together.


  ## RP Interest System

  Whenever your character takes an Acting Action (Says, Whispers, Radio Messaging, Emotes, Subtles) you gain points towards a half-hourly payout. When that check runs you gain a small income for Characterization. This system is not
  built around the concept of adding the total number of Acting Actions together, it instead runs a check on the number of people who participated in viewing your Acting and the overall length of your best emotes.

  This system is designed to reward players who are proactive about the world around them, who react with emotion and with characterization. Due to the design taking your best Acting Action sums it is also largely protected from spamming, as you gain nothing
  from simply repeating the same message over and over again.

  The amount of payout varies heavily, and can lean anywhere between 200 to aproximately 1300 per half hour period.  Which ultimately means you have more cash to burn on things you otherwise never would have purchased, or can fulfil shipborn roles such as
  travelling chefs, musicians, etc with a fair bit of ease.  This system also works as a safety net for players who have gotten themselves into a low cash situation, allowing them to roleplay their way out of it instead of feeling like they need to take
  drastic actions.


  ## Emotes and Subtle Changes

  We have made changes to the emotes and subtle system, they are listed here.
  - Emotes are not visible through walls.
  - Talking is audible from further than visual range

</Document>
