<Document>
  # Diona

 ### Homeworld
  Unknown

  ### Temperment
  Diona are generally straight forward.  They are not fans of lying, deception, or chicanery.  Their species is especially long lived as well, so as such they tend to be patient and future looking.


  ### Secondary Species of Interest
  Moths - Diona tend to be a bit distrustful of Moths, understanding that it is unreasonable to do so but the deeper knowledge that their biology would allow them to break down a Diona's plant fibers is too unsettling to fully ignore.

  Arachnids - Diona are generally aware of Arachnids fascionation with them but find their friendships to be a bit difficult due to what most Diona assume is a misplaced instinct.

  Harpy - The Harpies are generally appreciated by Diona as a whole, their ability to mimic sounds often being something that can entrance many Diona.


  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobDiona" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  They can't wear shoes, but are not slowed by Kudzu.
  They get hungry and thirsty slower.
  Being so sturdy, they can withstand the shock from FTL jumps without falling to the ground.
  Their "blood" is tree sap and can't be metabolised from Iron.
  Being plants, Weed Killer poisons them, while Robust Harvest heals them (but not without risk when overused!)

  They take [color=#1e90ff]30% less Blunt damage and 20% less Slash damage[/color];
  but [color=#ffa500]50% more Heat damage, 20% more Shock damage, and they can easily
  catch on fire when receiving enough Heat damage from *any* source.[/color]

  ## Make Like A Tree And Leave
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="FloraTree" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  Being exposed to too much Robust Harvest will cause a Diona to grow out of control, turning into an immobile tree (dropping all their equipment).
  Cutting down the tree will "restore" the Diona to their mobile state.

  ## Diona Nymphs
  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobDionaNymph" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobDionaNymph" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobDionaNymph" Caption=""/>
  </Box>
  After death, a Diona can voluntarily destroy their own body, releasing their "internal organs" as three Nymphs,
  with the player taking control of the Brain Nymph.
  It can talk but has no hands or inventory, and can't do much.

  After 10 minutes, a Nymph can reform into a whole Diona. This will be a new randomised body with a random name,
  and there will be little to no evidence beyond their word about who they were before.


</Document>
